# **David Lea**

2656 Wakefield Rd. Berkley, MI 48072

Phone: (248) 930-2439 E-Mail: dave@davelea.me

# **Summary**

Certified Salesforce administrator with 3 years of experience administrating a large Salesforce deployment. Highly motivated to solve problems and make processes simpler for end-users by using tools on the Force.com platform. Self-starter that thrives in environments that are open to new ideas and technologies.

# **Professional Experience**

### Salesforce Administrator / Business System Analyst

# Wayne State University - Detroit, MI

#### May 2014 - Present

- Managed end-user support for all of the university's 215 Salesforce users across both the Sales and Service Clouds.
- Led meetings with management and technical staff to document requirements, and design solutions to address business needs using the Force.com platform.
- Established, maintained, and documented custom profiles and role hierarchies, security settings, sharing rules, applications, custom objects, custom fields, page layouts, workflow rules, validation rules, and custom report types within the university's Salesforce instance.
- Built over 100 applications using Salesforce Visual Workflow and Visualforce to automate or enhance business processes for multiple university departments including event check-in, phone scripts, and smart data entry.
- Co-presented on Wayne State University's use of Visual Workflow at Dreamforce 2014.
- Authored 7 Apex Triggers (cross-object rollups, advanced data validation) and maintained a library of 355 Apex Classes (external integrations, data processing, Visualforce controllers).

#### Salesforce Administrator / Data Analyst

#### Wayne State University - Detroit, MI

#### **September 2012 - May 2014**

- Responsible for daily Salesforce routines, including monitoring data entry for accurate and nonduplicative records, creating custom reports and dashboards, and managing a custom contact matching process.
- Preparing and executing mass data uploads and updates into the Salesforce using the Apex Data Loader.
- Creating and using technical training documentation to roll out new Salesforce applications and procedures to Wayne State University end users.
- Monitoring technical support requests from Salesforce users, and using customer service skills, to resolve issues in a timely manner.

#### **Independent Salesforce Consultant**

## January 2014 - Present

- Led meetings with customers to establish project requirements and delivery dates.
- Designed and configured custom solutions using custom objects, custom fields, workflow rules, and formulas to meet requirements on multiple projects.
- Installed and setup third party tools from the Salesforce AppExchange.

#### **Team Leader**

## Target - Southfield, MI

#### November 2003 - September 2012

Logistics Team Leader

- Led a logistics team of 30+ team members, responsible for operational duties including freight flow, data integrity, overstock, and shipping and receiving.
- Responsible for hiring, coaching, and developing all team members on the logistics team.
- Maintained and trained all team members on R/F units and related applications.

Asset Protection Team Leader

- Led a security team, providing a safe and secure store for team members and guests.
- Maintained and troubleshot a network of digital video cameras and switches.

# Certifications

- Salesforce Certified Administrator
- Comp TIA A+ Certification

## **Technical Skills**

- Apex, Visualforce, HTML, CSS
- · Visual Workflow, Apex Data Loader, Jitterbit, FormAssembly, DemandTools, Excel

# **Education**

Wayne State University - College of Engineering

2013 - Present

Fourth year student pursuing a Bachelor of Science in Computer Science